www.tvsubtitles.net
The substance burns so hot,
it melts wood,
stone, even steel.
And, of course, flesh.
If I could tell you
how many crazy old men
I've seen making grand claims
about jars full of pig shit.
Our order does not deal
in pig shit.
King Stannis is my God.
He raised me up
and gave you a future
I could never have imagined.
And you think a Fire God
commanded all that?
- It was Stannis.
- Stannis is my king, but he's only a man.
Don't tell him that.
Does it give you joy
to scare people?
No, it gives me joy
to kill people.
Killing's the sweetest
thing there is.
You shipped off my only daughter
and now you want
to send my eldest son
to the battlefield to die.
He needs to be out there.
The men will fight more
fiercely seeing their king
fighting beside them instead of
hiding behind his mother's skirts.
Stannis two days from the capital
and the wolf at my doorstep.
Scouts assure us Robb Stark
won't risk
marching on Casterly Rock
until he's at full force.
He'll risk anything
at any time.
We'll ride at nightfall.
The Stark forces are distracted.
Now is the time to strike.
My dear nephew,
you do understand Stannis
Baratheon sails this way?
They say Stannis never smiles.
I'll give him a red smile.
If the wind holds, we'll reach
King's Landing in a day.
Will it hold?
Can't make promises
for the wind, Your Grace.
Stannis knows King's Landing.
He knows where
the walls are strongest
and he knows which gates
are weakest.
Mud gate.
That's where he'll land.
And if Stannis does attack
the mud gate, what do we have?
( Theme music playing )
♪ Game of Thrones 2x09 ♪
Blackwater
Original Air Date on May 27, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
Man:
That's it.
( Men coughing )
( Thunder rumbling )
The tide's against us.
Aye, but we have
the wind.
She'll blow us
straight to the gate.
You're coming home.
King's Landing hasn't
been home for 20 years.
I spent most of my life
dodging the Royal Fleet.
And now I'm sailing
right at them.
This is the Royal Fleet.
And you're not a smuggler anymore,
you're the high captain.
Of course there are several
Royal Fleets at the moment.
Not after tonight.
When the sun rises,
Stannis will sit
on the Iron Throne
and you will be his Hand.
- Gods be good.
- God.
Father, there is only one
and he watches over us.
- But not over them?
- Over all of us.
The people of King's Landing
did not choose the false King
Joffrey Baratheon.
They will be glad to see
his head on a spike.
Well, first we have
to put it there.
Our ships outnumber
theirs 10 to one.
Our army outnumber
theirs five to one.
Those walls have
never been breached.
And the men
guarding the walls,
when they see you,
they don't see a liberator.
They see a stranger come
to set their city on fire.
I have faith
in the Lord of Light.
in our cause.
And I have faith
in my captain.
( Thunder crashes )
Are you afraid, my lion?
If the city falls, Stannis will
burn every Lannister he can find.
Of course I'm afraid.
I won't let
them hurt you.
I'm a Lannister.
I don't have
a choice in all this.
But it's not your war.
It is now.
You can't fuck your way
out of everything.
I have so far.
Do you remember what you said
when you met me in your tent?
That I should make love
to you like it was your
last day on this earth.
Pycelle:
As you know, Your Grace,
it is not only
the sworn duty of a Maester
to carry out the wishes
of the house he serves,
but also to offer guidance
and counsel
in times of war.
Your words are always
wise and measured.
- If you could--
- If anything,
a Maester's duties
become more urgent
in times of war
and turmoil.
I remember back
in the days of king--
You brought me something?
Yes.
Essence of Nightshade
is as dangerous
as it is efficacious.
A single drop
in a cup of wine
suffices to soothe
ragged nerves.
Three drops
will bring on a deep
and dreamless sleep.
10 drops, however--
I know what 10 drops
will bring.
- Your Grace, if I may ask--
- You may not.
You must have
a lot of work to do.
I'm sure many brave men
will need your wisdom soon.
Yes.
A siege is very--
Be careful on the stairs, Grand Maester.
There are so many.
( Sighs )
Your Grace.
( Men singing )
♪ and so he spoke ♪
♪ that Lord of Castamere ♪
♪ but now the rains ♪
♪ weep o'er his halls ♪
♪ with no one there
to hear ♪
♪ yes, now the rains ♪
♪ weep o'er his halls ♪
♪ and not a soul to hear. ♪
- To the boys!
- Lannisters!
Where'd you learn
the Lannister song?
- Drunk Lannisters.
- ( Men laugh )
You've got
a pretty voice.
Thank you very much.
And I like
your nose.
How many times
you break it?
Well, now let's see.
First time I was five.
Me mom smacked me
with an iron poker.
Ooh.
Oh, it wasn't me
she was aiming at.
She was trying
for me little brother.
Now he was a real pest.
Second time I was nine.
Got in a scrap
with a few older boys.
They won.
Third time...
Eh, you don't want to know
about the third time.
Poor nose.
Don't feel sorry
for him.
He'll be halfway up your ass
before the night's through.
( Men laugh )
( Chatter stops )
Welcome, friends.
This round's on me.
I don't think
he likes me.
You think
you're a hard man?
( Chuckles, slaps )
- I know it.
- ( Men laugh )
It's warm in here.
We've got beautiful women
and good brown ale.
Plenty for everyone.
And all you want
is to put one of us
in the cold ground
with no women
to keep us company.
Oh, there's women
in the ground.
I put some there myself.
So have you.
You like fucking
and drinking
and singing.
But killing--
killing's the thing
you love.
You're just like me.
Only smaller.
And quicker.
Eh?
( Chuckles )
Your Lord Imp
is gonna miss you.
Aye.
( Slaps )
I expect he will someday.
- ( Bell tolling )
- Man: Here we are.
( Chatter )
One more drink
before the war?
Shall we?
I've always
hated the bells.
They ring for horror--
a dead king,
a city under siege.
- A wedding.
- Exactly.
Podrick, is that it?
"Is that it?"
Nice touch.
As if you don't know the name
of every boy in town.
I'm not entirely sure
what you're suggesting.
I'm entirely sure you're entirely
sure what I'm suggesting.
Do you trust him?
Oddly enough, I do.
Good.
The map you asked for.
There must be 20 miles
of tunnels beneath the city.
Closer to 50.
The Targaryens built this
city to withstand a siege
and to provide escape
if necessary.
I'm not escaping.
Strange as it sounds,
I'm the captain of the ship.
And if the ship goes down,
I go with her.
That is good to hear.
Though I'm sure many
captains say the same
while their ship
is afloat.
You look well suited
for battle, My Lord.
Well, I'm not.
For all our sakes,
I hope you are wrong.
My little birds tell me
that Stannis Baratheon
has taken up with a Red
Priestess from Asshai.
What of it?
You don't believe in
the old powers, My Lord?
Blood spells, curses, shape-shifting--
what do you think?
I think you believe
in what you see
and in what those
you trust have seen.
You probably don't
entirely trust me.
Mm, don't take it
personally.
I don't entirely
trust myself.
And yet I have seen things
and heard things--
things you have not,
things I wish I had not.
I don't believe I've ever
told you how I was cut.
No, I don't believe
you have.
One day I will.
The dark arts have provided
Lord Stannis with his armies
and paved his path
to our door.
For a man in service to such
powers to sit on the Iron Throne,
I can think
of nothing worse.
And tonight,
I believe you are the only man
who can stop him.
( Tolling continues )
They're welcoming
the new king.
I've never known bells
to mean surrender.
They want to play
music with us? Let's play.
- Drums.
- Drums!
( Men shouting )
Tyrion:
Remember, wait till the shit--
Bronn:
The ships are in the bay.
They must be far enough
in so they won't be--
I know what "in" means.
- Do you know how to use that?
- I chopped wood once.
No, I watched my brother
chopping wood.
I saw you kill a man
with a shield.
You'll be unstoppable
with an axe.
- Don't get killed.
- Nor you, my friend.
- Oh, are we friends now?
- Of course we are.
Just because I pay you
for your services doesn't
diminish our friendship.
Enhances it, really.
Oh, enhances.
Fancy word for a sellsword.
Been spending time
with fancy folks.
Lady Sansa
and, uh, Sheila.
Shae.
Shae, yes.
Surely my sister
has asked you to join
the other highborn ladies
in Maegor's holdfast.
She has, My Lord,
but King Joffrey sent
for me to see him off.
Sansa.
He's been a great
romantic, my nephew.
Joffrey:
Sansa, come here.
I will pray for your
safe return, My Lord.
Will you?
Just as I pray
for the King's.
Stay safe, My Lady.
And you, my lion.
Your king rides forth
to battle.
You should see him
off with a kiss.
My new blade.
Hearteater I've named it.
Kiss it.
You'll kiss it again
when I return
and taste
my Uncle's blood.
Will you slay him
yourself?
If Stannis is fool enough
to come near me.
So you'll be outside the gates
fighting in the Vanguard?
A king doesn't discuss
battle plans
with stupid girls.
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
You're right, I'm stupid.
Of course you'll be
in the Vanguard.
They say my brother
Robb always goes
where the fighting
is thickest.
And he is only
a pretender.
Your brother's turn
will come.
Then you can lick his blood
off Hearteater, too.
Some of those boys
will never come back.
Joffrey will.
The worst ones
always live.
Shh.
Come, My Lady.
( Men shouting )
( Neighing )
( Distant drums beating )
- Where's our fleet?
- On the way.
Why isn't it here now?
They're coming.
Hound, tell the Hand that his
King has asked him a question.
The King has asked
you a question.
Ser Lancel, tell the Hound
to tell the king
that the Hand
is extremely busy.
The Hand of the King
would like me to tell
you to tell the King--
If I tell the Hound
to cut you in half,
he'll do it without
a second thought.
That would make me
the Quarterman.
It just doesn't have
the same ring to it.
Cut me in half and I won't
be able to give the signal.
No signal, no plan.
No plan and Stannis
Baratheon sacks this city,
takes the Iron Throne,
puts your pinched
little head atop
a gate somewhere.
It might be quite amusing,
except that my head
would be up there, too.
I've never much
liked my head,
but I don't want to see
it removed just yet.
( Drums beating )
Where are their ships?
It is wise to attack at night.
We took them by surprise.
Lord Varys knows what you had
for breakfast three days ago.
There are
no surprises here.
If it's true there is dissension
in their ranks,
maybe their sailors
have mutinied.
Maybe.
( Babies crying )
I don't know why
she wants me here.
She's always saying
how stupid I am. She hates me.
Maybe she hates you less than
she hates everyone else.
I doubt it.
Maybe she's
jealous of you.
Why would she
be jealous?
Sansa.
I was wondering where
our little dove had flown.
You look pale, child.
Is your red flower
still blooming?
Yes.
Fitting, isn't it?
The men will bleed out there
and you will bleed in here.
Pour Lady Sansa
some wine.
I'm not thirsty,
Your Grace.
So? I didn't
offer you water.
What's he doing here?
Ser Ilyn?
He's here to defend us.
When the axes smash
down those doors,
you may be glad
to have him.
But we have guards
to defend us.
Guards we have paid.
Should the city fall,
they'll be the first ones
out of the doors.
The lads caught a groom and
two maids trying to sneak away
with a stolen horse
and some gold cups.
The battle's first
traitors.
Have Ser Ilyn
see to them.
Put their heads on spikes outside
the stables as a warning.
The only way to keep
the small folk loyal
is to make certain they fear you
more than they do the enemy.
Remember that if you ever
hope to become a queen.
( Door closes )
You said he was here
to protect us.
He is.
Traitors are a danger
to us all.
More wine.
- ( Distant drums beating )
- ( Men shouting )
There they are.
- Archers to their marks.
- Archers, to your marks!
Man:
Archers!
Nock your arrows!
Man:
Nock arrows!
- Hold fast.
- Man: Hold fast!
What are you doing?
We need to attack them.
- Hold fast.
- Man: Boulders ready!
Man #2:
Hold fast!
There's only one ship.
Where are the rest of them?
Where are
the rest of them?!
There's only one ship.
Archers, stand to!
Man the below!
- Nock!
- Man: Nock and set!
Draw!
Hold.
Man:
Hold!
There's no one on board.
Man:
More rocks coming up!
Hold.
Wildfire.
Steer clear!
Matthos!
Get down!
( Men screaming )
( Laughs )
( Men wailing )
( Men wailing, shouting )
- Prepare to land.
- Your Grace...
The dwarf has played
his little trick.
- The wildfire--
- He can only play it once.
We're too far
from the gates.
The fire,
their archers--
hundreds will die.
Thousands.
Come with me
and take this city!
( Cheering )
Sansa, come here,
little dove.
My queen.
What are you doing?
Praying.
You're perfect,
aren't you?
Praying.
What are you praying for?
For the Gods to have
mercy on us all.
Oh.
On all of us?
- Yes, Your Grace.
- Even me?
Of course,
Your Grace.
Even Joffrey?
- Joffrey is my--
- Oh, shut up, you little fool.
Praying to the Gods
to have mercy on us all.
The Gods have no mercy.
That's why they're Gods.
My father told me that
when he caught me praying.
My mother just died,
you see.
I didn't really understand
the concept of death,
the finality of it.
I thought that if I prayed
very, very hard,
the Gods would return
my mother to me. I was four.
Your father doesn't
believe in the Gods?
He believes in them, he just
doesn't like them very much.
One for her.
Here.
Sit.
Drink.
Not like that.
Drink, girl.
I should have been
born a man.
I'd rather face 1,000 swords
than be shut up inside
with this flock
of frightened hens.
They are your guests
under your protection.
You asked them here.
It was expected of me,
as it will be of you if you ever
become Joffrey's queen.
If my wretched brother
should somehow prevail,
these hens will return
to their cocks
and crow of how my courage
inspired them,
lifted their spirits.
And if the city
should fall?
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
The Red Keep
should hold for a time,
long enough for me
to go to the walls
and yield to Lord Stannis
in person.
If it were anyone else
outside those gates,
I might have hoped
for a private audience.
But this is Stannis Baratheon.
I'd have a better chance
of seducing his horse.
Have I shocked you,
little dove?
Tears aren't a woman's
only weapon.
The best one's
between your legs.
Learn how to use it.
Drink.
Do you have any notion
of what happens
when a city is sacked?
No, you wouldn't,
would you?
If the city falls,
these fine women
should be in
for a bit of a rape.
Half of them
will have bastards
in their bellies
come the morning.
You'll be glad of
your red flower then.
When a man's blood
is up,
anything with tits
looks good.
A precious thing like you
will look very, very good.
A slice of cake
just waiting to be eaten.
- More pressure!
- ( Men shouting, grunting )
- Pull! Pull!
- That's it, men!
Pull! Pull!
That's it!
Steady!
He's a serious man--
Stannis Baratheon.
They're coming.
They're coming ashore.
Rain fire on them.
Archers!
There are too many.
Hound, form a welcome party
for any Baratheon troop
that manages to touch
solid ground.
Pod, run to
the King's gate.
Bring any men
guarding it here now.
Yes, My Lord.
Let's go. Stannis is sending
us fresh meat.
You, too.
Any of these flaming
fucking arrows come near me,
I'll strangle you
with your own guts.
( Men shouting )
Pull, pull! Go!
Nock!
Draw!
- Draw!
( Men shouting )
Man:
Kill the Lannisters!
Loose!
Man:
Form the line!
Stannis!
- Draw!
- Loose!
Man: They cannot
breach the wall!
Yah!
The mud gate, go now!
First and second squads, to the gate!
To the mud gate!
Hound: Any man dies
with a clean sword,
I'll rape
his fucking corpse.
( Screams )
Cersei: When we were young,
Jaime and I,
we looked so much alike.
Even our father
couldn't tell us apart.
I could never understand why
they treated us differently.
Jaime was taught to fight
with sword and lance and mace,
and I was taught to smile
and sing and please.
He was heir
to Casterly Rock
and I was sold to some
stranger like a horse
to be ridden
whenever he desired.
You were Robert's queen.
And you will be
Joffrey's. Enjoy.
I don't think
I know this one.
Pretty.
That's the worst
curtsy I've ever seen.
Here, it's not difficult.
I mastered it when I was four.
Straighten your back
and bend.
Better.
You learn fast.
How long have you been
in Lady Sansa's service?
A few weeks,
Your Grace.
When did you
leave Lorath?
I had a Lorathi
handmaiden once.
But she was
a nobleman's daughter.
You're not.
When did you come
to Westeros?
10 years ago,
Your Grace.
From Lorathi commoner
to the Red Keep
in 10 years, all without
learning how to curtsy.
I imagine that's
a very interesting story.
What's your name?
Shae, Your Grace.
Tell us a story, Shae.
- When I was 13, I--
- ( Door opens )
Your Grace!
What news?
The Imp has set
the river afire.
Hundreds of ships
are burning, maybe more.
Stannis's fleet
destroyed, but...
( Quietly )
But-- but his troops
have landed outside
the city walls.
Where is Joffrey?
On the battlements
with Lord Tyrion.
Bring him back
inside at once.
- But, Your Grace--
- What?
The King's presence
is good for morale.
Bring him back
to his chambers now.
- Not here?
- With the women and children?
Do you want him to be mocked as
a coward for the rest of his life?
- No, but I--
- Now!
When I told you about
Ser Ilyn earlier, I lied.
Do you want to hear
the truth?
You want to know why
he's really here?
He's here for us.
Stannis may take the city,
he may take the throne,
but he will not
take us alive.
( Screaming )
( Arrow thunks )
- Man: Ah! Help me!
- ( Man #2 shouting )
Man:
We'd better run!
Men:
Fall back!
Get the ladders up!
( Grunts )
Faster, you bastards!
Faster!
Come on, kill the scum!
Someone bring me a drink.
Fuck the water.
Bring me wine.
Can I get you
some iced milk
and a nice bowl
of raspberries, too?
Eat shit, dwarf.
You're on the wrong
side of the wall.
I lost half my men.
The Blackwater's on fire.
Dog, I command you to go
back out there and fight.
You're Kingsguard, Clegane.
You must beat them back or
they're going to take this city--
your king's city.
( Sniffles )
Fuck the Kingsguard.
Fuck the city.
Fuck the King.
( Men shouting )
Man:
Loose!
Man #2:
Put your backs into it!
All right, get up!
Man:
Loose!
Man #2:
Clear!
- Forward!
- ( Men shouting )
Loose!
Forward ladders!
Man: They're coming
up the wall!
Archers on the north wall!
- Man #2: Heave!
- ( Men grunting )
Your Grace,
the queen has sent me to bring
you back to the Red Keep.
If you won't defend your
own city, why should they?
What would you
have me do?
Lead.
Get down there
and lead your people
against the invaders
who want to kill them.
What did my mother
say exactly?
Did she have urgent
business with me?
She did not say,
Your Grace.
Man:
All men to the battlements!
Ser Boros,
Ser Mandon,
stay with my Uncle
and represent the king
on the field of battle.
Man:
Archers, hold your line
or I'll kill you myself.
Man:
Stand fast!
No!
Get up, you fool.
Man:
We need more arrows!
Where is the king?
- Why isn't he with us?
- Man #2: Who are we fighting for?
Man #3:
Who leads us?
( Softly )
I'll lead the attack.
I'll lead the attack!
- Man: Yes?
- Man #2: What are you talking about?
Pod, my helmet.
Ser Mandon, you will bear
the King's banner.
Men, form up.
Men--
- men!
- Come on.
They say I'm half a man.
But what does that make
the lot of you?
The only way out
is through the gates.
And they're at the gates.
There's another way out.
I'm going to show you.
We'll come out behind them
and fuck them in their asses.
- ( Men laugh )
- ( Pounding )
- ( Men grunting )
- Man: Heave!
Heave!
Don't fight for your king
and don't fight
for his kingdoms.
Don't fight for honor.
Don't fight for glory.
Don't fight for riches,
because you won't get any.
This is your city
Stannis means to sack.
That's your gate
he's ramming.
If he gets in, it will be
your houses he burns,
your gold he steals,
your women he will rape.
- Heave! Heave!
- ( Men grunting )
Those are brave me
knocking at our door.
Let's go kill them.
( Cheering )
The battle is lost,
Your Grace.
Stannis's troops
are at the gates.
When the Gold Cloaks
saw the king leaving,
they lost all heart.
Where is my son?
I want to escort him
back to the battle.
Why do I care what you want?
- Bring me--
- Now listen to me-- ah!
( Groaning )
Don't be afraid. The queen has
raised the drawbridge.
This is the safest
place we can be.
Joffrey's not hurt.
He's fighting bravely.
His knights have
rallied behind him.
They will save the city.
Shall we sing a hymn?
♪ Gentle mother ♪
♪ font of mercy ♪
♪ save our sons
from war, we pray ♪
- ♪ gentle-- ♪ ( Gasps )
- You must go.
Run to your chamber
and bar your door.
Stannis won't hurt you.
This one will.
Come with me.
I need to say goodbye
to someone.
The queen said
they'd rape everyone.
No one is raping me.
Go. Run.
Women: ♪ save our sons
from war, we pray. ♪
( Combatant screams )
- The lady is starting to panic.
- ( Gasps )
What are you doing here?
Not here for long.
- I'm going.
- Where?
Someplace that
isn't burning.
North, might be.
Could be.
What about the king?
He can die just fine
on his own.
I can take you with me.
Take you to Winterfell.
I'll keep you safe.
Do you want to go home?
I'll be safe here.
Stannis won't hurt me.
Look at me.
Stannis is a killer.
The Lannisters
are killers.
Your father was a killer.
Your brother is a killer.
Your sons will be
killers someday.
The world is built
by killers.
So you'd better get
used to looking at them.
You won't hurt me.
No, little bird,
I won't hurt you.
- ( Men grunting )
- Heave! Heave!
Come on, you bastards!
Get up those ladders!
Ah!
Attack!
Roll it over!
( Men cheering )
( Chanting ) Halfman! Halfman!
Halfman! Halfman!
( Chanting continues )
Oh, fuck me.
( Shouting )
Shh.
Be calm, my sweet.
They're still fighting.
No one's going
to hurt you.
I'll tell you a story.
You know the one about the
mother lion and her little cub?
- They lived in the woods.
- The Kingswood.
Yes, my love.
In the Kingswood there lived
a mother and her cub.
She loved him very much.
But there were other things
that lived in the woods.
- Evil things.
- Like what?
Like stags.
Stags aren't evil.
They only eat grass.
And wolves.
My Lord.
Cersei: He could hear them
howling in the night.
The little cub
was frightened.
His mother said,
"You are a lion, my son.
You mustn't be afraid.
For one day all the beasts
will bow to you.
You will be king.
All the stags will bow.Ts
all the wolves will bow.
The bears in the north
and the foxes of the south,
all the birds in the sky
and the beasts in the sea--
they will all come
to you, little lion...
to rest a crown
upon your head."
And the cub said,
"Will I be strong
and fierce like my father?"
"Yes," said his mother.
"You will be strong and fierce
just like your father."
I will keep you safe,
my love.
I promise you.
( Doors open )
- ( Men shouting )
- Man: Back to the boats!
Stand and fight!
Stand and fight,
damn you!
No!
Father.
The battle is over.
We have won.
( Crying )
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪ "And who are you,"
the proud lord said ♪
♪ "that I must bow
so low? ♪
♪ only a cat
of a different coat ♪
♪ that's all the truth
I know ♪
♪ in a coat of gold
or a coat of red ♪
♪ a lion still
has claws ♪
♪ and mine are long
and sharp, My Lord ♪
♪ as long and sharp
as yours" ♪
♪ and so he spoke,
and so he spoke ♪
♪ that Lord of Castamere ♪
♪ but now the rains weep
o'ver his hall ♪
♪ with no one there
to hear ♪
♪ yes, now the rains weep
o'er his hall ♪
♪ and not a soul
to hear. ♪